const fadeInChoices = () => Array.from(
  document.querySelectorAll('.fade-in'))
    .map(choice => {
      choice.animate([
        { opacity: 100 },
        { opacity: 0 }, 
        { opacity: 100 },
      ], {
        duration: 1000,
        iterations: 1,
      }
  )
});

const randomize = (originalArray) => {
  const shuffledArray = [];
  
  do {
    const randomInteger = Math.floor(Math.random() * originalArray.length);
    if (shuffledArray.includes(randomInteger)) {
      continue;
    } else {
      shuffledArray.push(randomInteger);
    }
  } while (shuffledArray.length < originalArray.length);

  return shuffledArray.map(index => originalArray[index]);
}

const STATE = {
  NOT_STARTED: 0,
  IN_PROGRESS: 1,
  COMPLETED: 2,
};

const COMPETENCY_LEVELS = {
  0: 'Do you even wine?',
  1: 'Do you even wine?',
  2: 'You need more wine in your life',
  3: 'You need more wine in your life',
  4: 'Youâ€™re a 4 â€¦ but youâ€™re funny ðŸ˜Š',
  5: 'Youâ€™ve been to a tasting or two but could use some more sippin',
  6: 'Sips of success â€“ youâ€™re doing great!',
  7: 'Sips of success â€“ youâ€™re doing great!',
  8: 'Sip nâ€™ slay â€“ youâ€™re a wine snob!',
  9: 'Sip nâ€™ slay â€“ youâ€™re a wine snob!',
  10: 'Master Somm status achieved!!!',
};

const ROUNDS = [
  {
    question: `How many pounds of grapes are needed to make a bottle of wine?`,
    answer: `2.5 pounds`,
    choices: randomize([`10 pounds`, `2.5 pounds`, `61 pounds`, `0.7 pounds`])
  },
  {
    question: `The process by which grape sugar becomes alcohol is...`,
    answer: `Fermentation`,
    choices: randomize([`Carbonation`, `Fermentation`, `Yeastification`, `Ripening`]),
  },
  {
    question: `What compound in red grapes makes you tired?`,
    answer: `Melatonin`,
    choices: randomize([`Alcohol level`, `Melatonin`, `Grape color`, `Sugar level`]),
  },
  {
    question: `Which of the following external factors does not influence a grape varietyâ€™s flavor profile?`,
    answer: `Bottle size`,
    choices: randomize([`Weather`, `Soil`, `Aging style and time`, `Bottle size`]),
  },
  {
    question: `Which wine-making method gives wine a crisp and effervescent profile?`,
    answer: `Both Steel barrel aging AND Egg barrel aging`,
    choices: randomize([`Steel barrel aging`, `Oak barrel aging`, `Egg barrel aging`, `Both Steel barrel aging AND Egg barrel aging`]),
  },
  {
    question: `Which country is not a top-five producer of wine?`,
    answer: `Chile`,
    choices: randomize([`Italy`, `Spain`, `Argentina`, `Chile`]),
  },
  {
    question: `Which of the following is not one of the -S words of tasting?`,
    answer: `Stand`,
    choices: randomize([`Sip`, `Stand`, `Smell`, `Swirl`]),
  },
  {
    question: `Which of these is the most diverse grape?`,
    answer: `Sauvignon Blanc`,
    choices: randomize([`Merlot`, `Cabernet Sauvignon`, `Chardonnay`, `Sauvignon Blanc`]),
  },
  {
    question: `Which wine is associated with flavours of green bell pepper, grass, and gooseberry?`,
    answer: `Sauvignon Blanc`,
    choices: randomize([`Merlot`, `Cabernet Sauvignon`, `Chardonnay`, `Sauvignon Blanc`],) 
  },
  {
    question: `Where did winemaking begin?`,
    answer: `Georgia`,
    choices: randomize([`France`, `Argentina`, `Italy`, `Georgia`],) 
  }    
];

let CURRENT_ROUND = 0;

document.addEventListener('alpine:init', () => {
  Alpine.store('quiz', {
    choiceLabels: ['A', 'B', 'C', 'D'],
    competencyLevel: '',
    competencyText: '',
    guess: '',
    hasGuessed: false,
    currentRound: CURRENT_ROUND + 1,
    round: ROUNDS[CURRENT_ROUND],
    score: 0,
    state: STATE.NOT_STARTED,

    start () {
      this.state = STATE.IN_PROGRESS;

      document.querySelector('.quiz-container').classList.remove('bg-main');
    },
    
    guess (event) {
      if (this.hasGuessed) {
        return;
      }

      if (this.completed) {
        this.competencyLevel = COMPETENCY_LEVELS[this.score];
        
        return;
      }
      
      const choiceElementDOM = event.target;

      choiceElementDOM.id = 'chosen';

      const selectedChoice = this.round.choices[choiceElementDOM.id];
      if (selectedChoice === this.round.answer) {
        this.score += 1;
      }

      this.hasGuessed = true;
      this._showCorrectAnswer();
    },
    
    nextRound() {
      const nextRound = ROUNDS[CURRENT_ROUND + 1];
      if (nextRound) {
        this.hasGuessed = false;
        this.round = nextRound;
        this.currentRound += 1;
        
        CURRENT_ROUND += 1;
        
        fadeInChoices();
        this._hideNextButton();
        this._clearSelected();
      } else {
        this.state = STATE.COMPLETED;
        this.competencyText = COMPETENCY_LEVELS[this.score];
      }
    },
    
    _clearSelected() {
      document.getElementById('chosen').id = '';

      Array.from(document.querySelectorAll('.quiz-card')).forEach(choice => choice.classList.remove('red-border', 'green-border'));
      
      Array.from(document.querySelectorAll('.quiz-card-front')).forEach(card => card.classList.remove('quiz-card-front-flip'));
      Array.from(document.querySelectorAll('.quiz-card-back')).forEach(card => card.classList.remove('quiz-card-back-flip'));
    },

    _hideNextButton() {
      document.querySelector('.button-next').classList.add('opacity-0');
    },

    _showCorrectAnswer() {
      document.querySelector('.button-next').classList.remove('opacity-0');
      
      Array.from(document.querySelectorAll('.quiz-card-front')).forEach(card => {
        if (card.dataset.choice === this.round.answer || card.id === 'chosen') {
          card.classList.add('quiz-card-front-flip');
        }
      });
      Array.from(document.querySelectorAll('.quiz-card-back')).forEach(card => {
        
        if (card.dataset.choice === this.round.answer) {
          const chosenCardBackDOM = document.getElementById('chosen').parentElement.querySelector('.quiz-card-back');
          
          card.classList.add('quiz-card-back-flip');
          chosenCardBackDOM.classList.add('quiz-card-back-flip');
        }
      });
    },
  });
});
